JUSTIN HOCH

Andover, MN 55304

Phone: 763-334-2891 | Email: Justinonlycoding@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/justin-hoch-ob84651b6/

GitHub: https://github.com/Justinean

Portfolio: https://justinean.github.io/react-portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a 19 year old full stack web developer and I can create and maintain websites both on the front end and back end. In all my previous work experiences, I have been known in my past work experiences to have a bright personality that can help lift the spirits of coworkers who are struggling. I have graduated from high school with honors at a 3.5 gpa.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:

- English
- Basic spanish

Skills:

- Html w/ or w/o bootstrap
- CSS
- Javascript w/ or w/o JQuery
- React
- API implementation
- Node JS
- Express
- Sequelize
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- MERN Stack
- GraphQL api
- RESTful api

PROJECTS

BlitzandChaos — *Interactive Story*

An interactive story where the main character – YOU, the user – will embark on a mission to save the world from a DRAGON! The user will read a story and make decisions, which will determine the final outcome. In the end, you will either find a way to save everyone (including yourself) or be forced to watch everything burn in an unstoppable, fiery apocalypse. The choice is yours. Choose wisely.

Live link: https://justinean.github.io/BlitzandChaos

Repository: https://github.com/Justinean/BlitzandChaos

Password Generator — *Password Generator App*

A password generator that generates a random password when given specific criteria for the password such as length, and what characters to use.

Live link: https://justinean.github.io/password-generator

Repository: https://github.com/Justinean/password-generator

Weather Dashboard — Weather App

A weather dashboard that you can search for the weather using the postal code and the country of the location you want the weather of. It stores previously searched locations so you can just click on a button to display the weather of that location again. You can also clear the previously searched locations. The app displays the current weather, and a five day forecast, which tell you the temperature, weather conditions, wind, humidity, and the UV index.

Live link: https://github.com/Justinean/weather-dashboard

Repository: https://justinean.github.io/weather-dashboard/

Manage Me Now — Project Management App

A project and employee handle. Managers can create projects and tasks and assign those to employees. Employees can't change anything but they can change their profile pictures and view company projects and their own projects.

Live link: https://manage-me-now.herokuapp.com/login

Repository: https://github.com/Justinean/Manage-Me-Now

EXPERIENCE

Wal-Mart, Andover MN — Cashier

July 2019 - June 2020

- 2nd shift employee of the month.
- Over 1000 items/hour scanned.

Wal-Mart, Andover MN — *eCommerce Personal Shopper*

June 2020 - September 2020

• Multiple positive reviews by customers with my name listed.

Target, **Andover MN** — Fulfillment

September 2020 - December 2020

• One of the quickest pickers of the team (70-80 items/hour)

Holiday, Ham Lake MN — Cashier

January 2021 - August 2021

• The quickest cashier on the team so I was put on register most of the time.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Degree or Certification: University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

Andover High School, Minnesota — *Diploma*

September 2016 - June 2020

Graduated with honors with a 3.5 GPA.